What do you see?
¿Qué ves?
-Is a bird flying in the sky? -That's right.
¿Un pájaro volando por los cielos?
It flew over to the other side of the sun. Where did it go?
Voló hacia el otro lado del sol. ¿Adónde fue?
It must've gone to the other world.
Debe haber ido al otro mundo.
Can't you see? Take a good look.
¿No lo ves? Fíjate bien.
I can't see it.
No puedo verlo.
-Shall I help you see it? -Yes.
¿Te ayudo a verlo?
All right.
Muy bien.
Have a good look.
Fíjate bien.
The world we're living in consists of the part where we reside
Este mundo está dividido en el lugar donde vivimos
and the other part over there.
y la otra parte de allá.
This is where we live,
Nosotros vivimos aquí,
and the gods live in the other part of the world.
y los dioses viven en esa otra parte del mundo.
"The gods"?
¿Los dioses?
The world of the gods consists of the Land of Water,
El mundo de los dioses está formado por el Reino del Agua,
the Land of the Sky, and the Land of Earth.
del Cielo y de la Tierra,
They send deities to our world
los que envían deidades a nuestro mundo
to look after and protect nature in the human realm.
para proteger la naturaleza del reino humano.
Do they look after humans too?
¿Y también cuidan a los humanos?
Human beings will figure things out on their own.
Los seres humanos se las arreglan solos.
The Kings of the Land of Water, Land of the Sky, and Land of Earth
Los reyes del Reino del Agua, del Cielo y de la Tierra
were born with the fate of becoming rulers.
nacieron con el destino de convertirse en gobernantes.
The King of the Land of Water, from where all things originate,
El rey del Reino del Agua, desde donde nace todo,
is given absolute authority which makes him the King of the Kings.
con su autoridad absoluta, es el rey de los reyes.
In order to ascend to the throne, they must make their royal seals
Para ascender al trono, deben hacer su sello real
with the sacred stone that has a holy message engraved on it,
con las piedras sagradas del oráculo,
but that stone is kept by the gods who reside in the human world.
las cuales son protegidas por los dioses que viven en el mundo humano.
That means they have to come here and get the stone
¿Tienen que venir a buscarlas
if they wish to become the ruler of the divine world.
para gobernar el mundo divino?
That's correct.
Correcto.
But what if those deities refuse to give it to them?
¿Y si esos dioses se niegan a dárselas?
Only humans do things like that.
Solo los humanos harían eso.
But there's something I don't understand.
Pero hay algo que no entiendo.
Why is the sacred stone kept in the human world?
¿Por qué están las piedras sagradas en el mundo humano?
UNDYING CONNECTION BETWEEN PARENTS AND CHILDREN
LAZO ETERNO ENTRE PADRES E HIJOS
YEAR 2018
AÑO 2018
ONE YEAR AGO
UN AÑO ANTES
High Priest.
Sumo sacerdote.
It's about time the red tide rushed in.
Al fin llegó la marea roja.
The divine realm will welcome a new emperor after 3,000 years.
El reino divino tendrá un nuevo emperador después de 3000 años.
Where is Lord Habaek?
¿Y el señor Habaek?
I am beyond honored to be given this opportunity.
Me siento inmensamente honrado por esta oportunidad.
Thank you for your boundless generosity, Lord Habaek.
Gracias por su infinita generosidad, señor Habaek.
Painting your noble face
Pintar su noble rostro
is making me understand why the universe has chosen you
me hace entender por qué el universo lo eligió
to be our next king.
como nuestro próximo rey.
Now, please open your eyes...
Ahora, si pudiera abrir los ojos…
Please allow me to complete the most important part of this...
Por favor, permítame completar la parte más importante.
My lord, the High Priest asked me to pass along this message to you.
El sumo sacerdote me pidió que le diera un mensaje.
Tell him to stop sending me these messages.
Dile que deje de hacer eso.
Does he have that much to say? He does this every day.
¿Tanto tiene que decirme? Todos los días hace esto.
He said that the waters have reddened...
Dijo que las aguas enrojecieron
and that you should get ready.
y que debía prepararse.
Is His Majesty aware of it too?
¿Su majestad lo sabe?
He is delighted.
Está encantado.
He has been waiting for the red tide for a long time.
Ha estado esperando la marea roja por mucho tiempo.
He has been on the throne for eons.
Lleva eones en el trono.
He must be exhausted.
Debe estar exhausto.
This shows the locations of the three deities with the sacred stone.
Aquí están los tres dioses con las piedras sagradas.
This will lead you to them.
Esto lo ayudará a encontrarlos.
My lord.
Mi señor.
Mura is there from the Land of Water. The Land of Earth must've sent Judong.
El Reino del Agua envió a Mura, y el de la Tierra a Judong.
-What about the Land of the Sky? -It's Biryeom.
- ¿Y el del Cielo? - A Biryeom.
What...
¿Qué?
-Biryeom? -The enthronement must take place
- ¿A Biryeom? - La coronación debe ocurrir
after the seventh red tide,
luego de la séptima marea roja,
so you just have to come back with the sacred stone before that.
así que debe regresar con la piedras sagradas antes de eso.
-I'll come back right away. -Why?
- Volveré enseguida. - ¿Por qué?
The world of mankind is actually a pretty fun place.
El mundo de los humanos es muy divertido.
We have plenty of time before the last tide,
Falta bastante tiempo para la coronación.
-so you should have some fun. -I'm not interested.
- Debería divertirse. - No me interesa.
By the way, why do we still have to follow such meaningless customs?
¿Por qué debemos mantener estas costumbres sin sentido?
Nothing in this world is meaningless.
Todo en este mundo tiene un sentido.
Anyway,
En fin,
I'll get rid of such meaningless customs as soon as I ascend to the throne.
me desharé de esas costumbres apenas ascienda al trono.
Sure.
Claro, podrá hacer lo que quiera cuando sea rey.
It sounds like you're doubting whether I can really do it.
¿Acaso dudas que pueda lograrlo?
Of course not.
Claro que no.
You were born to be a king, my lord.
Nació para ser rey, mi señor.
The throne will become yours, even if you don't do anything.
El trono será suyo aunque no haga nada.
No one can refute that unless they're crazy.
Solo alguien loco podría negar eso.
Becoming a king in the divine realm has nothing to do with humans,
Ser rey del reino divino no tiene que ver con los humanos,
so why is the sacred stone kept there?
¿por qué están ahí las piedras?
What a hassle.
Qué molestia.
Well...
Bueno…
you have a question,
Tiene una pregunta,
so you should stay there for a while and find the answer.
quizá debería buscar la respuesta allá.
It wasn't a question.
No era una pregunta.
Oh, right. You've heard about the divine servants, right?
Ha oído de los sirvientes divinos, ¿no?
Humans who made a pledge to serve us generation after generation.
Son humanos que prometieron servirnos.
If you run into problems, find descendants of that family.
Si tiene problemas, busque a sus descendientes.
Showing this to them
Al mostrarles este amuleto, los hará despertar.
Then they'll serve you as their god.
Le servirán como su dios.
I don't need it. I won't look for them.
No lo necesito. No los buscaré.
It's a girl.
Es una chica.
Would you like to see her face?
¿Quiere ver su rostro?
She's not bad.
Es bonita.
No need.
No hace falta.
Namsuri will be escorting you.
Namsuri lo escoltará.
Keep the sacred pendant on you at all times, even if it's inconvenient.
Lleve siempre el amuleto del sirviente.
Don't leave it with your clothes.
No lo deje por ahí.
The Land of the Sky has gone crazy.
El Reino del Cielo se volvió loco.
They put Biryeom in charge of looking after the sky.
Enviaron a Biryeom.
That punk is incapable of doing any work.
Es un bueno para nada.
Why do you hate Biryeom so much?
¿Por qué lo odia tanto?
You two used to be close friends.
Eran buenos amigos.
He has no class.
No tiene clase.
Also,
Además,
he's not reliable.
no es confiable.
You should learn about the human world before you go.
Debería estudiar el mundo humano.
That's why I'm taking you with me.
Por eso te llevo conmigo.
I heard you've been to the world of mankind.
Escuché que has ido antes.
Sure. I do know a lot about it.
Sí, sé mucho al respecto.
The moment you pass the Divine Gate, you'll feel a sting.
Sentirá un pinchazo al pasar por el portal divino.
But it's not that bad.
No duele mucho.
Get me the best kinds of clothes that humans wear.
Consígueme la mejor ropa que usen los humanos.
And don't forget a gift for Mura.
Y un regalo para Mura.
Have you seen the servant yet?
¿Vio a la sirviente? Oí que es una chica.
Is she pretty?
¿Es linda?
Oh, yes. Sure.
Sí, seguro.
I received a revelation from the alien gods of the planet Intro Q 2544.
Recibí un mensaje de los dioses alienígenas
My supervisor is TF 1004. He seemed to be in a huge rush.
Mi supervisor es TF 1004.
I see. What else?
Ya veo. ¿Qué más?
Here on Earth, there are partners who carry out such divine messages like I do.
Otras personas también reciben mensajes divinos como yo.
The organization is spread throughout the world.
La organización está en todo el mundo.
But the strange thing is,
Pero es extraño,
why did they send this divine message to me
¿por qué me enviaron el mensaje a mí en vez de al socio de EE. UU.?
Right. I wonder why.
Claro, ¿por qué será?
"Inform Obama. World peace is under threat."
"Informar a Obama. La paz mundial está en peligro".
That's what it means.
Eso significa.
Are you...
¿Acaso usted es…?
What should I do? I don't know the address.
¿Qué debo hacer? No conozco su ubicación.
Do you know that he's out of the White Roof House?
¿Sabe que salió de la Casa Blanca?
So, even you don't believe me.
Así que tampoco no me cree.
Don't say that. You're my patient, so--
No diga eso, es mi paciente…
What? Did you just call me a patient?
¿Me llamó "paciente"?
Again?
¿Otra vez?
-Hey! -I didn't mean...
No quise decir eso.
-As a patient-- -I'm not a patient!
- Como paciente… - ¡No soy un paciente!
Right, Mr. Ma Bong-yeol.
Sí, Sr. Ma Bong-yeol. Conseguiré la ubicación de Obama.
-Gosh! -Don't lie to my face!
- ¡Dios mío! - ¡No me mienta!
You don't even believe me!
¡Ni siquiera me cree!
Doctor. Doctor, please.
Doctora, por favor.
No one believes me. World peace is--
Nadie me cree. La paz mundial…
Let go, please.
- ¡Suélteme! - …está en peligro.
-Sir. Mr. Ma. -World peace
- ¡Señor Ma! - La paz mundial
-is under threat. -Please let go of her.
- está en peligro. - Por favor, suéltela.
It's true that world peace is under threat.
Es cierto que la paz mundial está en peligro.
You...
¿Puedes hablar nuestro idioma?
Of course. It's nice to meet you.
Por supuesto. Gusto en conocerlo.
I'm glad to meet you.
Me alegra conocerte.
Let's get out of here.
Salgamos de aquí.
This way. Go on.
Por aquí. Vamos.
Let's go.
Vamos.
-How could you communicate with him? -I observed him.
- ¿Cómo hiciste eso? - Lo observé.
It sounds like total bullshit, but it's systematic like the Korean alphabet.
Suena incoherente, pero se parece mucho al coreano.
He's very smart, you know.
Es muy inteligente.
You're much better than me.
Eres mucho mejor que yo.
His family wanted to keep him in the hospital, right?
¿Su familia quería enviarlo al hospital?
I can't handle him. Schedule an appointment.
No puedo con él. Agenda una cita.
-Come on. Don't give up so easily. -You think I'm giving up easily?
- No te rindas tan fácilmente. - ¿Crees que eso hago?
Hey, I've been treating him for a year.
Hace un año que lo trato.
Admitting failure is never easy.
No es fácil admitirlo. ¿Debería seguir por orgullo?
-I'm sick of it. -I get it.
- Estoy harta. - Lo entiendo.
Half of these are payment reminders.
La mitad son recordatorios de pago.
DA DA FINANCIAL
BANCO DA DA
The bank called to say they can't give you
El banco dijo que no puede darte otra extensión.
Why not?
¿Por qué no?
The clinic is not doing well, and you don't pay the interest on time.
A la clínica no le va bien y no pagas a tiempo.
Then what? Do they want this clinic to be shut down?
- ¿Acaso quieren que cierre? - Supongo.
Get out.
Vete.
-Give me your gown. I'll wash it for you. -Forget it.
- Puedo lavar tu bata. - Olvídalo.
Do you want to grab a drink with me?
¿Quieres ir a beber algo?
Why would I grab a drink with you?
¿Por qué bebería algo contigo?
I forgot to give you this. It's for your land in Gangwon Province.
Olvidé darte esto. Es de tu terreno en Gangwon.
PROPERTY TAX
IMPUESTO A LA PROPIEDAD
It still hasn't sold?
¿Aún no lo vendes?
Who'd buy such a useless piece of land filled with stones?
¿Quién compraría un terreno lleno de piedras?
I really didn't need to inherit this.
No necesitaba heredar esto.
We're really behind on our rent as well.
Estamos atrasados con la renta.
And you've already spent half of the rent deposit.
Y ya gastaste la mitad del depósito.
By the way, why do you still work for me?
¿Por qué sigues trabajando para mí?
Quit now.
¡Renuncia!
I want to repay the kindness I received.
Quiero devolver el favor.
-Your father-- -Shut it.
- Tu padre… - Cállate.
I don't want to hear it.
No quiero hablar de eso.
By the way,
Por cierto, ¿aún sueñas con irte del país para siempre?
Yes. As soon as I pay off all my debt,
Sí, apenas pague todas mis deudas,
I'll pack up and move to Vanuatu.
empacaré y me mudaré a Vanuatu.
Just find a guy who will clear your debt for you
Buscate a un tipo que pague tus deudas
and stay here.
y quédate aquí.
No way. I don't like Korea.
De ninguna manera. No me gusta Corea.
Or maybe men don't like you.
O quizá no les gustas a los chicos.
Hey, I even got a diamond ring from a wealthy man.
Oye, un hombre con mucho dinero me dio un anillo de diamantes.
Found it.
Lo encontré.
I actually got this ring from a man. Why wouldn't he believe me?
¿Por qué no creyó que me regalaron este anillo?
I found you because you were obviously meant to be mine.
Estabas destinado a que te encontrara.
I can't believe his name is Ahn Bin.
No puedo creer que se llamara Ahn Bin.
It sounds so childish.
Suena tan infantil.
Take care of all the bills and my interest payments.
Te venderé para pagar mis deudas.
Vanuatu, my love.
Mi querida Vanuatu.
Yes.
Sí.
That's how life is supposed to be.
Así debería ser la vida.
I can't see a single star in this polluted country.
No puedo ver ni una estrella en este país tan contaminado.
I want money! Please help me roll in money.
¡Deseo tener mucho dinero!
Hey, woman.
Oye, mujer.
Woman.
Mujer.
I shall give you the honor of lending me this.
Tendrás el honor de prestarme esto.
Hey, woman.
Oye, mujer.
Wake up.
Despierta.
You shouldn't sleep here.
No debes dormir aquí.
This woman is such a nuisance.
Pero qué mujer más molesta.
What?
¿Qué?
What's going on?
¿Qué pasó?
Hey, you thief!
¡Ladrón!
How dare you call me a thief, you rude woman!
¿Cómo te atreves a decirme ladrón?
I shall punish you later.
Te castigaré luego.
What has happened?
¿Qué pasó?
Namsuri. What happened to him?
¿Y qué le pasó a Namsuri?
My lord! You made it down here safe and sound.
¡Mi señor! Llegó sano y salvo.
-What happened? -I don't know.
- ¿Qué pasó? - No lo sé.
I landed over there.
Aterricé ahí.
What happened to you?
¿Qué le pasó?
That's what I wanted to ask you. Why are you wearing my clothes?
Eso me pregunto. ¿Por qué tienes mi ropa?
Pardon?
¿Qué?
How did this happen?
¿Cómo pasó esto?
Let's switch.
Cambiémonos.
This is strange.
Qué raro.
The Divine Gate looks different from what I saw 55 years ago.
El portal divino es diferente a como era hace 55 años.
Look closely.
Pon atención.
Here, a lot can change, even in just ten years.
Las cosas cambian mucho aquí, incluso en diez años.
The land that is used as the Divine Gate never changes.
El terreno del portal divino nunca cambia.
Then something must have gone wrong on our way here.
Entonces algo ocurrió mientras veníamos.
-Where's the map? -Pardon? Don't you have it?
- ¿Y el mapa? - ¿Qué? ¿No lo tiene?
Gosh!
Cielos.
Use your abilities to find it.
Use sus habilidades.
Did you find it, my lord?
¿Lo encontró?
What's wrong?
¿Qué pasa?
It's strange.
Qué raro.
I feel as if...
Siento como si algo
something...
hubiera escapado…
has left my body.
…de mi cuerpo.
"Something"?
¿Algo?
How could this happen?
¿Cómo pasó esto?
You lost your abilities?
- ¿Perdió sus poderes? - Volvamos al Reino del Agua.
-Take me to the Divine Gate. -We can't go back now.
- Llévame al portal divino. - No puedo.
All gods must fulfill their duties in order to return.
Debe cumplir con su deber para poder regresar.
I told you to study.
Le dije que estudiara.
First, let's find the descendant of the servant.
Busquemos a la sirvienta.
We need her help now.
Necesitamos ayuda.
You don't have it?
¿No tiene el amuleto?
What are we going to do now?
¿Qué haremos ahora?
-Let me get a change of clothes first. -I'm okay.
Busquemos ropa primero.
Please stay put.
Quédese aquí.
Don't be so confident and arrogant all the time.
No actúe tan confiado y arrogante.
And don't order anyone around, okay?
Y no le dé órdenes a nadie, ¿bien?
All right.
Está bien.
Gosh, this is crazy.
Cielos, qué locura.
No.
No.
That can't be.
No puede ser.
It's probably just a temporary phenomenon.
Debe ser algo temporal.
I couldn't use my power during my first visit
No pude usar mi poder cuando fui al Reino del Cielo por primera vez.
So where are you now?
¿Dónde estás?
How many times do I have to tell you? He stole my diamond ring.
Ya te dije, me robaron mi anillo de diamantes.
I'm not drunk, okay?
No estoy ebria.
I am Habaek.
Soy Habaek.
Why did I come to the park?
¿Por qué vine al parque?
I told you that I'm here to find my diamond ring.
Ya te dije. Vine a buscar mi anillo de diamantes.
What? I'm delusional?
¿Qué? ¿Crees que estoy loca?
Hey.
Oye.
Where are you?
¿Dónde estás?
I am...
Soy…
Habaek.
…Habaek.
Just answer my question.
Solo responde mi pregunta.
I am...
Soy…
Habaek.
…Habaek.
Where are you, you idiot?
¿Dónde estás, idiota?
I am Habaek.
Soy Habaek.
-Where? -I am Habaek!
- ¿Dónde? - ¡Soy Habaek!
Jeez, that totally scared me.
Vaya, qué susto.
See? I am Habaek.
¿Ves? Soy Habaek.
It's working fine.
Está funcionando bien.
There's nothing wrong with it.
No hay problemas.
Turn it off for now.
Apágala por ahora.
Let's test it a few more times.
Probemos de nuevo en un rato.
It's that woman.
Es esa mujer.
What is he doing? Is he walking toward me?
¿Qué? ¿Se está acercando?
Do I know that guy?
¿Acaso lo conozco?
No, I don't know him.
No, no lo conozco.
Hey, woman.
Oye, mujer.
You're mistaken. I'm only borrowing it.
Te equivocas. Solo lo pedí prestado.
Sorry?
¿Disculpa?
-Me? -If you tell me your name
- ¿Me hablas a mí? - Dame tus datos
and where you live, I'll have Namsuri pay you back.
y Namsuri te devolverá todo.
What do you need?
¿Qué necesitas?
Seriously, even such a handsome guy can be mentally ill.
Hasta los guapos tienen problemas mentales.
You should go home. Your family must be worried.
Deberías ir a casa. Tu familia debe estar preocupada.
-Don't hesitate to tell me. -It's fine.
- No dudes en decirme. - Estoy bien.
How insolent.
Qué insolente.
I asked you a question. I didn't say you could go.
No dije que pudieras irte.
For goodness' sake.
Por el amor de Dios.
I...
Yo…
Could he be delusional?
¿Estará delirando?
What is it that you need?
¿Qué necesitas?
Money?
¿Dinero?
What is that?
¿Qué es eso?
Never mind. You should hurry home.
Olvídalo, deberías ir a casa. Buenas noches.
-Let go! -Your name and where you live.
- ¡Suéltame! - Dame tus datos.
Let go of my hand, or I'll call the police.
Llamaré a la policía.
-I said, let go! -Doctor!
- ¡Suéltame! - ¡Doctora!
What are you doing? Let go!
¿Qué haces? ¡Suéltame!
Let go of her. Don't do this.
Suéltela. No haga esto.
Such insolence. How dare you!
¿Cómo te atreves?
What happened to your forehead?
¿Qué te pasó en la frente?
-Did he hit you? -No, it's fine. Let's go.
- ¿Te golpeó? - No, está bien. Vamos.
I'm the God of Water,
Soy el Dios del Agua,
the next king of the Land of Water and the next emperor of the gods,
el próximo rey del Reino del Agua y emperador de los dioses,
Habaek.
Habaek.
I knew it.
Lo sabía.
He's absorbed by grandiose delusions.
Tiene delirios de grandeza.
Here.
Tome.
Come visit us. It's not far from here.
Venga a visitarnos.
Our doctor is very good.
Nuestra doctora es muy buena.
I hope to see you soon.
Nos vemos.
You know you're cut out to be a psychiatrist, right?
Naciste para ser psiquiatra.
People who need you come to you day and night.
Los pacientes te encuentran de día y noche.
Be quiet.
Cállate.
I'm sure you'll only find people like him, even in Vanuatu.
Seguramente te pasaría lo mismo en Vanuatu.
Wouldn't it be better to stay here?
¿No sería mejor quedarte?
I think Korea is still better.
Aún creo que Corea es mejor.
Where's the nearest police station?
¿Dónde está la policía?
Why do you ask?
¿Por qué? ¿Harás una denuncia?
I'm going to file a report about my diamond ring.
Es por mi anillo de diamantes.
Are you still drunk?
¿Sigues ebria?
They'll look into it and get in touch with us.
Investigarán el caso.
THE POLICE PROMISE YOU SAFETY AND HAPPINESS
LA POLICÍA LE PROMETE SEGURIDAD Y FELICIDAD
Are you mad at me?
¿Estás enojada?
I don't think you believe me.
No creo que me creas.
Let's say I believe you about the diamond ring buried under a tree.
Digamos que sí creo que enterraste ese anillo,
But you also went on about the star frantically moving from left to right.
pero también dijiste que había una estrella que se movía.
And the thief who fell from the sky didn't take your wallet.
Y el ladrón que cayó del cielo no robó tu billetera.
Why? So that you'd have money to get around?
¿Por qué no la robaría?
It really happened!
¡En verdad pasó!
Shall I get you a glass of cold water or what?
¿Quieres un poco de agua fría?
Right, she doesn't like cold water. How about some warm water?
Cierto, no te gusta fría.
What took you so long?
¿Por qué tardaste tanto?
I tried to get some information about this world from humans
Obtuve información de este mundo
and find a place for you to stay tonight.
y hallé un lugar para dormir.
Let's go, my lord. I've found a good place.
Vamos, es un buen lugar.
-It's close to water too. -There's no need.
- Está cerca del agua. - No.
-I got my abilities back. -Seriously?
- Recuperé mis habilidades. - ¿En serio?
The water you see behind us
El agua que ves detrás de nosotros se elevó según mis órdenes.
I knew it.
Lo sabía.
Then please go ahead and turn it into gold.
Entonces, convierta esto en oro.
You'll be comfortable here since it's very close to water.
Como está cerca del agua, estará muy cómodo.
This is it.
Aquí estamos.
I took a while because I had to inflate this.
Me demoré en inflarlo.
A man gave it to me earlier, saying I should visit.
Me dijeron que visitara este lugar.
You spoke with a human?
¿Habló con un humano?
I told you not to say a word.
Le dije que no…
"Blessed Mental Health,
¿Santa Salud Mental, doctora Yu Sang-yu?
What?
¿Qué?
Oh, I was just reading what's written here.
Estaba leyendo.
You can't read the human alphabet, right?
¿No sabe leer esto?
Sleep well, my lord.
Que descanse.
I'll stand guard here all night.
Haré guardia toda la noche.
I'll try to find the map as soon as the sun comes up.
Buscaré el mapa apenas amanezca.
In the human world, money can solve most problems.
En el mundo humano, el dinero puede resolver casi todo.
What is it that you need?
¿Qué necesitas?
Money?
¿Dinero?
You're not pronouncing that word correctly.
No lo pronunciaste bien.
It's "money," you dummy.
Debes alargar la E, tonto.
Happy Bank also called for you.
Happy Bank también te llamó.
-Did you take another loan out? -It wasn't me.
- ¿Pediste otro préstamo? - No fui yo.
Right.
Es cierto.
Selling the diamond ring won't solve my problems.
Vender el anillo no resolverá mis problemas.
"Money"?
¿Dinero?
What is that?
¿Qué es eso?
Right, that probably allows him to be carefree.
Claro, por eso no tiene preocupaciones.
That's how life should be.
Así debería ser la vida.
Let's talk while looking around the resort.
Hablemos mientras caminamos.
Is the food and beverage team going first?
¿Está lista la comida?
We have a banquet with 200 Chinese guests scheduled for today.
Tenemos un banquete con 200 invitados chinos.
The owner of a Chinese harbor construction company will be there.
Irá el dueño de una constructora de puertos.
You should attend it so that--
Podría ir para…
I won't need to attend it as he's not a national VIP.
No iré. No es un cliente importante.
-Anything from the planning team? -Yes, sir.
- ¿Y la planificación? - Sí.
This is the British company's revised construction proposal.
El plan de construcción de la compañía británica,
The location is the same. It's the site you checked the other day.
en la ubicación que revisó el otro día.
It's not bad. As long as everything is okay with the site...
No está mal, mientras no haya problemas.
I'll go through it.
Lo revisaré.
Any bank-related updates for me?
¿Y los bancos?
Yes, sir. A bank approached us
Uno de ellos ofreció bajar los intereses de algunos préstamos.
They want to discuss it with you over a meal.
Quieren discutirlo durante el almuerzo.
Do I have to be there?
¿Tengo que ir?
I think it'll be good to meet with them in person.
Sería bueno que los viera en persona.
After that, they also succeeded in detecting a second gravity wave.
También detectaron una segunda onda gravitacional,
It's possible
y es posible que llegue
that third and fourth waves are arriving as we speak,
una tercera y cuarta onda en cualquier momento.
and there might have been a time and space warp in Seoul.
Además, pareciera que ocurrió una distorsión espacial en Seúl.
We'll learn more about gravity waves on Amazing Science today.
Aprenda más del tema hoy en Ciencia Increíble.
Hello.
Hola.
-Any word from the police station? -No, they haven't called.
¿Llamó la policía?
Apparently, there might have been a time and space warp in Seoul yesterday.
Parece que hubo una distorsión espacial ayer.
Perhaps your diamond ring disappeared when that happened?
Quizá por eso desapareció tu anillo.
I bought it at the Dongdaemun Market early this morning.
La compré en el mercado hoy.
-Wear it for now. -You should've gotten more sleep.
- Es por mientras. - No debiste molestarte.
The doctors' gown is so important for doctors.
La bata de doctor es importante.
-Doesn't your stomach hurt? -I'm not hungover.
- ¿Y tu estómago? - No tengo resaca.
-Did you have breakfast? -You're nagging again.
- ¿Desayunaste? - Deja de fastidiar.
You have no food at home, right?
No tienes comida, ¿cierto?
I should stop by and make some side dishes.
- Debería ir a cocinarte. - ¿Quieres morir?
He called again.
volvió a llamar.
I took care of everything with the insurance company.
- El seguro se ocupó de eso. - ¿Sí?
By the way, when will you go to the bank?
¿Y cuándo irás al banco?
Putting it off won't solve the problem.
Aplazarlo no resolverá nada.
I know that too.
Ya lo sé.
-Any appointments in the morning? -No, obviously.
¿Tengo alguna cita?
Your afternoon schedule is empty too, so you can go whenever you want.
A la tarde tampoco, así que estás libre.
The interest too. You always make the payments late.
Siempre hace sus pagos fuera de plazo.
On top of that, you've been managing your credit very poorly.
Además, ha manejado muy mal su crédito.
You received an extremely low rating in last year's evaluation.
Tuvo una calificación muy baja el año pasado.
Please review it again.
Revíselo de nuevo, por favor.
I've paid all of my taxes. I'm just struggling temporarily.
Sí pago mis impuestos. Solo tengo problemas temporales.
Psychiatric clinics do very well these days.
- Las clínicas psiquiátricas son exitosas. - Bueno,
you can pay part of the amount that you owe
podría pagar lo que debe
and switch to an interest rate that's around seven percent,
y cambiar a una tasa de interés del siete por ciento,
but I'm not sure if the evaluation team will accept this.
pero no sé si el equipo lo aceptará.
Seven percent?
¿Siete por ciento?
How can the interest rate jump from four to seven percent?
¿Subiría de cuatro a siete?
Please look into it for me, then.
Vea si se puede, por favor.
WARM WATER
AGUA TIBIA
Gosh, where did he go?
Dios, ¿adónde fue?
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH NURSE YU SANG-YU
SANTA SALUD MENTAL DRA. YU SANG-YU
Why is this taking so long?
¿Por qué tarda tanto?
Excuse me.
Disculpe.
Just a moment, please.
Espere, por favor.
Do I have to wait much longer?
¿Falta mucho?
I have to go back to my clinic to attend to patients.
Debo ir a atender pacientes.
Just a moment, please.
Un momento, por favor.
Gosh! My goodness!
Dios mío.
Sir, did you have a good lunch?
Señor, ¿disfrutó el almuerzo?
Would you like a cup of pour over coffee made with organic beans?
¿Quiere un café hecho con granos orgánicos?
If you choose to go with our loan services,
Le podríamos ofrecer
-we can offer you one-percent interest. -What? One percent?
- un interés del uno por ciento. - ¿Uno por ciento?
Excuse me.
Disculpen.
-I told you to wait. -I can't wait all day.
- Le dije que esperara. - No puedo.
You've kept me waiting since this morning.
Llevo toda la mañana esperando.
I'm not asking for a new loan. I just want an extension.
Solo estoy pidiendo una extensión.
Is it that hard to check it for me?
¿Es eso tan difícil?
And why are you walking around with my personal information?
¿Y por qué andas con mi información personal?
Well...
Bueno…
Please wait outside.
Espere afuera, por favor.
I told you I won't wait any longer.
No esperaré más.
And why do I have to pay seven percent when he's getting one percent?
¿Y por qué debo pagar siete por ciento, pero él uno?
How can you treat your customers so unfairly?
Esto es injusto.
-Well, that's-- -I know. I know the reason.
- Bueno… - Ya sé la razón.
But this is out of line.
Pero esto es inaceptable.
The difference between one and seven percent is huge!
¡Es demasiada diferencia!
Please help her first.
Atiéndanla primero.
You can discuss this with my finance team.
Pueden hablar con mi equipo de finanzas.
Sir, wait. You can't just leave like this.
Señor, no puede irse así.
-What did you say? -You just cut in line.
- ¿Qué? - Se adelantó a su turno.
He's leaving because he's upset.
Se va porque está molesto.
That is not true.
Eso no es cierto.
It's the bank's fault for revealing the interest rate to other customers.
Es culpa del banco revelar las tasas de otros clientes.
-You're the one who should apologize. -Sorry?
- Ustedes deberían disculparse. - ¿Perdón?
I'll ask the bank if you could get the loan.
- Le ayudaré a conseguir el préstamo. - ¿Por qué haría eso por mí?
You don't seem to know how to accept kindness.
Parece que no sabe aceptar ayuda.
Then instead of bothering the bank staff regarding your interest rate,
Quizá en vez de exigir un menor interés,
you should work harder to earn money on your own.
debería trabajar más duro.
-Please visit our clinic. -Okay.
- Visite nuestra clínica. - Bien.
-Right. -Excuse me, sir. Please visit...
- Sí. - Disculpe, visite…
No, wait. Stop!
¡No, pare!
Why would you scrape off bird poop with our business card?
¿Por qué limpió la caca de pájaro con eso?
Seriously, why would you do that?
En serio, ¿por qué lo hizo?
-My goodness. -What's going on?
¿Qué sucede?
It's nothing, sir.
No es nada, señor.
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
Why did you scrape off bird poop with our business card?
¿Por qué usó nuestra tarjeta para eso?
-Why? -Please calm down.
- ¿Por qué? - Cálmese.
Please give me a call. I'll take care of this.
Por favor, llámeme. Yo me encargaré.
A business card is the face of that business.
La tarjetas son importantes.
You practically wiped bird poop with our clinic's reputation!
Manchó la reputación de nuestra clínica.
-Enough. Let's go. -Think about it.
Suficiente.
Why do you think cars have windshield wipers?
Use el limpiaparabrisas.
You're supposed to wipe things off with this.
Para eso sirve.
What's the point of having a big car?
¿Por qué no lo usa?
My gosh, I'm so sorry.
Dios mío, lo siento mucho.
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH NURSE YU SANG-YU
SANTA SALUD MENTAL
A psychiatric clinic?
¿Una clínica psiquiátrica?
I'll call you when I get an estimate of the repair cost.
Lo llamaré por los daños.
My lord.
Mi señor.
Where's the map? Did you find it?
¿Encontraste el mapa?
I couldn't find it anywhere.
No lo encontré.
I think we lost it on our way down here.
Creo que lo perdimos al bajar.
On our way here?
¿Al venir aquí?
-Does that mean we can't find it? -That's right.
- ¿No podemos encontrarlo? - Así es.
By the way, what are you doing out here? I told you to stay home.
Por cierto, le dije que se quedara en casa.
"Home"?
¿En casa?
You slept so soundly last night. I thought you were going to stand guard.
Dormiste bien anoche. Creí que harías guardia.
I must've fallen asleep because I was tired and hungry.
Bueno, estaba cansado y hambriento.
-You were hungry? -Yes.
- ¿Tenías hambre? - Sí.
I get hungry around mealtimes just like humans do.
Me da hambre, como a los humanos.
You probably don't even know what hunger feels like.
Quizá ni sepa cómo se siente eso.
Do I have to listen to you whining like this?
¿Tengo que escuchar tus lloriqueos?
No.
No.
Are you that hungry?
¿Tienes hambre?
Yes, I'm quite hungry.
Sí, bastante.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I can't even take care of a loyal servant like you.
Ni siquiera puedo cuidar a un sirviente leal como tú.
How can I become a good king when I'm this incompetent?
¿Cómo podré ser un buen rey?
What? No! That is not true, my lord!
¿Qué? ¡Eso no es cierto, mi señor!
Don't tell me you were actually expecting me to say that.
¿En serio esperabas que dijera eso?
Of course not.
Claro que no.
By the way, what is that thing?
Por cierto, ¿qué es esa cosa?
Well, that's...
Bueno, eso…
It's not food.
…no es comida.
-Let's go to that place. -Sorry? Where?
Vamos a aquel lugar.
The Divine Gate.
Al portal divino.
The divine servants have been guarding that place,
Los sirvientes divinos que lo vigilan nos dirán sobre la descendiente.
What? Are you planning to meet the descendant?
¿Qué? ¿Irá a ver a la descendiente?
I should give that servant a chance to faithfully serve me...
Le daré la oportunidad de servirme fielmente,
as the generous and dutiful god that I am.
como el dios generoso y responsable que soy.
What should we do?
¿Qué hacemos?
What if that wiper costs a fortune?
¿Y si el limpiaparabrisas cuesta una fortuna?
Then I might have to move out of my place.
Quizá tenga que mudarme de mi casa.
Why did you have to get all riled up like that?
¿Por qué te enojaste tanto?
Because he wiped bird poop with our business card.
Porque limpió la caca de pájaro con nuestra tarjeta.
You love your job too much.
Amas demasiado tu trabajo.
Why did it have to be that guy's car?
¿Por qué tenía que ser el auto de ese tipo?
Are you calling Mr. Min?
¿Estás llamando al señor Min?
-Ask him if we can pay less. -Mr. Min, my foot!
- Pídele pagar menos. - No lo estoy llamando.
Jeez, this realtor never answers my calls.
Este agente inmobiliario nunca me contesta.
Forget it.
Olvídalo.
-I have to go to Gangwon Province. -Right now?
- Debo ir a Gangwon. - ¿Ahora?
You should probably change your tires first.
Deberías cambiar los neumáticos.
You also need to change the brake fluid,
Y el líquido de frenos, el asistente de navegación y…
The windshield wiper.
El limpiaparabrisas.
Why isn't this working again?
¿Por qué no funciona?
Must you make it so obvious that you're a second-hand car?
Maldito auto de segunda mano.
My gosh.
Dios mío.
There we go.
Muy bien.
Did you say you need to go to Jeongbong Village?
¿Van a la aldea Jeongbong?
You need to go straight.
Deben ir derecho.
Just keep going that way.
Sigan por ese camino.
Then turn left when you feel like you've arrived at the right place.
Luego giren a la izquierda por un rato
Then keep going and turn right when you feel like you've walked enough,
y luego a la derecha por otro rato
and you'll eventually arrive at the village. Okay?
y al fin llegarán a la aldea, ¿entendieron?
What did he say to us just now?
¿Qué nos acaba de decir?
He just meant that it's not too far from here.
Que no está muy lejos.
Don't worry. I've been here several times.
No se preocupe. He venido varias veces.
No one has called about that land for the past five years.
No han preguntado por el terreno en cinco años.
That's why I asked you to put up a sign
Por eso le pedí que anunciara
and tell people that the land is for sale.
que el terreno está a la venta.
Jeez, okay. I heard you.
Está bien, ya la escuché.
I came here to ask if I could lower the price to sell it urgently.
Vine a pedirle que bajara el precio para venderlo urgentemente.
Even if you lowered the price,
Aunque bajara el precio,
nobody would want to buy such a useless piece of land.
nadie querría un terreno tan inútil.
Sir.
Señor,
I know it's useless, but you shouldn't say that to the landowner.
sé que es inútil, pero no debería decir eso.
So, how much?
¿A cuánto?
-Is it going to be half the price? -What?
- ¿A la mitad del precio? - ¿Qué?
This is where we were supposed to land.
Aquí debíamos aterrizar. Los humanos no pueden ver el portal.
Why did they build the gate on such an unimpressive piece of land?
¿Por está en un terreno tan mediocre?
By the way, that servant won't know a thing. What do we do?
Por cierto, la sirvienta no sabrá nada.
We need to show her the pendant
Debe mostrarle el amuleto para que sepa que es su sirvienta.
Don't worry.
No te preocupes.
I have a plan.
Tengo un plan.
What's your plan?
¿Cuál?
She'll fall for my charm,
Quedará encantada conmigo
so she'll naturally want to serve me.
y querrá servirme naturalmente.
If that doesn't work, I'll have to use my last resort.
Y si eso no funciona, tendré que usar mi último recurso.
And what might that be?
¿Y cuál es ese?
What? No, you can't do that.
¿Qué? No puede hacer eso.
-Why not? -You should never do that.
- ¿Por qué no? - Nunca debe hacer eso.
Then she'll forget everything,
y entonces se olvidará de todo, pero no podremos hacerlo si hace eso.
That would be too torturous for a human.
Sería demasiado doloroso para un humano.
You've been talking nonsense nonstop since yesterday.
Has estado hablando tonterías sin parar desde ayer.
Most importantly, you've lost your power. How will that even work?
Pero perdió sus poderes. ¿Cómo funcionaría?
What does that have to do with my power? Am I not a god without my power?
¿Qué tiene que ver eso? ¿Acaso no soy un dios?
Why don't you take my place, then?
¿Por qué no tomas mi lugar entonces?
My gosh, how could you say such a thing? No way, my lord.
¿Cómo puede decir algo así? De ninguna manera.
Excuse me.
Disculpen.
May I ask what brings you here?
¿Qué los trae por aquí?
I own this land.
Es mi terreno.
It was you.
Eras tú.
Let go of her. Don't do this.
Suéltela. No haga esto.
I'm the God of Water,
Soy el Dios del Agua,
the next king of the Land of Water, and the next emperor of the gods,
el próximo rey del Reino del Agua y emperador de los dioses,
Habaek.
Habaek.
What is he doing here?
¿Qué hace él aquí?
-Are you the owner of this land? -Yes, I am.
- ¿Es la dueña del terreno? - Así es.
-Are you here to buy this land? -Why would I buy my own land?
- ¿Quieren comprarlo? - Este lugar es mío.
What?
¿Qué?
I've looked all over for you, my faithful servant.
Te busqué por todos lados, mi fiel sirvienta.
I'm very glad to finally meet you.
Me alegra mucho conocerte al fin.
You should be grateful...
Deberías agradecer
that I'm glad to meet you.
que me alegre conocerte.
What are you doing?
- ¿Qué haces? - ¿Cómo te atreves?
You know you're cut out to be a psychiatrist, right?
Naciste para ser psiquiatra.
People who need you come to you day and night.
Los pacientes te encuentran de día y noche.
I need to go see Yeom-mi.
Debo ir a ver a Yeom-mi. Creo que es hora.
Please give me a heads-up before you do anything.
Por favor, avíseme antes de hacer algo.
Hey, Yeom-mi. Are you free tonight?
Yeon-mi, ¿estás libre esta noche?
No, you must make time for me. We need to meet.
No, debes hacerte el tiempo. Tengo que hablar contigo.
I'm in Gangwon Province right now. Oh, gosh!
Estoy en Gangwon.
Why? What's wrong?
¿Por qué? ¿Qué pasa?
Hey, I'll call you later.
Te llamo luego.
Are you okay? Let me see.
¿Estás bien? Déjame ver.
No, I'm fine.
No, estoy bien.
-He is not fine. -Right, I don't think I'm fine.
- No está bien. - No me siento bien.
I'm not fine.
No estoy bien.
You've entered the route to your destination.
Estás en ruta a tu destino.
I'll drop you off at a hospital nearby.
Los dejaré en un hospital cercano.
Let's call the insurance company there.
Llamemos al seguro ahí.
-No. We're coming with you. -Turn left.
- No, iremos contigo. - Gire a la izquierda.
Excuse me.
Disculpa.
He said he's not fine. He can't go all the way to Seoul.
Dijo que no está bien. No podemos ir hasta Seúl.
And can't you talk politely?
Y sé más respetuoso.
I don't know what you mean. Just try to have an awakening soon.
No sé qué dices, solo intenta despertar, así entenderás todo.
Understanding the situation will make things so much easier.
Eso facilitaría mucho las cosas.
What is he saying?
¿Qué está diciendo?
Look. Is there a specific clinic that you normally go to?
¿Vas a alguna clínica en particular?
If not, you can come to my...
Podrías ir a mi…
What am I saying?
¿Qué estoy diciendo?
Excuse me.
Disculpa.
I'm a doctor. Your friend here is--
Soy doctora, y tu amigo está…
He's not my friend. He's my servant.
No es mi amigo. Es mi sirviente.
Your servant...
¿Tu sirviente?
I mean, that guy sitting next to you
Bueno, parece que está bien.
I'm taking you with me because I don't want to get sued,
Solo los estoy llevando para que no me demanden.
I don't think I came this way.
No creo haber venido por aquí.
Turn right.
Gire a la derecha.
There's no road that turns right.
No hay un camino que gire a la derecha.
Go straight ahead until further instruction.
Siga derecho hasta nuevo aviso.
I don't think I'm going in the right direction.
No creo que vaya en la dirección correcta.
Turn right.
Gire a la derecha.
Turn left.
Gire a la izquierda.
Go straight ahead until further instruction.
Siga derecho hasta nuevo aviso.
Make a U-turn.
Haga un giro en U.
Turn left.
Gire a la izquierda.
-This is nuts. -Beware of the bend on your left.
- Qué locura. - Cuidado con la curva.
Go straight.
Siga derecho.
-There's no road here! -Then make a P-turn.
- ¡No hay más camino! - Haga un giro en P.
-Where are you telling me to go? -This is an unpaved road.
¿A dónde me estás llevando?
Go straight ahead. Please drive safely.
Siga derecho. Conduzca con cuidado.
-Are you tired? -Yes.
- ¿Estás cansada? - Sí.
What can I do for you?
¿En qué puedo ayudarte?
Nothing.
En nada.
Do you want me to drive?
¿Quieres que conduzca?
Do you have a driver's license?
- ¿Tienes licencia de conducir? - ¿Qué es eso?
Never mind.
Descuida.
Doctors should never let their patients drive.
No debería dejar que un paciente conduzca.
Turn right.
Gire a la derecha.
SERVICE UNAVAILABLE
SERVICIO NO DISPONIBLE
No!
¡No!
What's going on?
¿Qué sucede?
The car stopped because it ran out of gas.
- Nos quedamos sin gasolina. - Pues ve a buscar.
How?
¿Cómo?
Can I use your phone?
¿Puedo usar tu celular?
Your cell phone.
Tu celular.
Don't you have one?
¿No tienes uno?
Fine. Let's walk, then.
Bueno, caminemos. Seguro encontraremos a alguien.
Let's borrow a cell phone and call my insurance company,
Así podremos llamar a mi aseguradora
or we can try to go buy gas ourselves.
o comprar gasolina.
I don't understand what you're saying,
No entiendo lo que dices, pero deberías descansar.
-What? -You said you're tired.
- ¿Qué? - Estás cansada.
Stay here and get some rest. Namsuri will go by himself.
Descansa aquí. Namsuri irá solo.
But he's hurt.
Pero está herido.
Yes, I'm in pain.
Sí, estoy sufriendo.
-He's not hurt. -I think I'm okay now.
- Está bien. - Ya estoy bien.
-I feel fine. -Go on.
- Me siento bien. - Adelante.
No, it's okay. I'll go. It won't take long.
Está bien, yo iré. No tardaré mucho.
My gosh, what are you doing?
Dios mío, ¿qué estás haciendo?
I don't even know where I am now.
Ni siquiera sé dónde estoy.
Wait.
Espera.
Yes?
¿Sí?
My license plate number
Mi número de placa y el de la aseguradora.
And here's some money for gas. Oh, just a second.
Y dinero para la gasolina.
I almost forgot to give you this.
Casi olvido esto.
All right.
Está bien.
Why is everything...
¿Por qué
so difficult today?
todo me sale mal hoy?
Excuse me.
Disculpa.
You can wait inside the car.
Puedes esperar en el auto.
I'm okay, so you go ahead and rest up in the car.
Descansa adentro. Ya estoy bien.
My name is Habaek, not "Excuse me."
Me llamo Habaek, no "Disculpa".
I'm the God of Water, the next king of the Land of Water,
Soy el Dios del Agua y próximo rey de los dioses.
And...
Y también
I am your master.
soy tu maestro.
Ha...
Me llamo…
baek.
…Habaek.
Gosh, I keep forgetting that he's mentally ill.
Sigo olvidando que tiene problemas mentales.
Excuse...
Disculpa…
I mean, Mr. Habaek.
Es decir, señor Habaek.
Why do you think that you're the God of Water?
¿Por qué cree que es el Dios del Agua?
What kind of question is that?
¿Qué pregunta es esa?
Then let me ask you this. Why do you think you're human?
Es como si te preguntara por qué crees que eres humana.
Fine.
Está bien.
Then,
Entonces,
what exactly is the God of Water?
¿qué es exactamente el Dios del Agua?
What are you trying to do right now?
¿Qué intentas hacer?
Are you seeking to gain knowledge?
¿Quieres obtener conocimiento?
It seems like you wish to talk about the essence of the world.
Parece que quieres hablar de la esencia del mundo.
Listen to me carefully.
Pon atención.
The God of Water, the God of the Sky, and the God of Earth.
Los dioses del Agua, del Cielo y de la Tierra
We are equal to nature itself.
somos como la naturaleza misma.
Thus,
Por lo tanto,
I am nature.
yo soy la naturaleza.
-Are you talking about the TV show? -I said, I am nature.
- ¿Hablas del show de TV? - Que soy la naturaleza
-The show, I Am a Natural Person? -No, I am nature. More importantly,
Hay un show con ese nombre.
I am the most essential part of nature.
Soy la esencia de la naturaleza.
What?
¿Qué?
I mean, he looks completely normal.
Se ve completamente normal.
Stop peeping at me.
Deja de mirarme.
I can see it even with my eyes closed.
Sé que me estás mirando.
I'm so used to others looking at me like that.
Estoy acostumbrado a que me miren así.
Sure,
Seguro,
I bet.
ya me imagino.
You have...
Tiene familia, ¿cierto?
I can say that I do, but then I can also say that I don't.
Podría decirse que sí, como también que no.
The notion of family is different in the divine realm.
La idea de "familia" es diferente en el reino divino.
Then who's that guy--
¿Y qué hay del tipo…?
I told you that he's my servant. Like you.
Te dije que es mi sirviente, al igual que tú.
He's my servant from the divine realm,
Es mi sirviente del reino divino, y tú lo eres del mundo humano.
-Hey, servant. -Yes?
- Oye, sirvienta. - ¿Sí?
-Hey. -Call me Lord Habaek!
- ¡Oye! - ¡Llámame señor Habaek!
Is money really what you need...
¿Es dinero lo que más necesitas?
Why do you ask?
¿Por qué?
Why do humans need money so much?
¿Por qué los humanos necesitan dinero?
It's because money can make you happy.
Porque el dinero puede hacerte feliz.
You too?
¿A ti también?
Yes. Why?
Sí, ¿por qué?
I think..
Creo que puedo ayudarte con eso.
But not right now.
Pero no ahora.
I'm in a bit of a situation now.
Es un poco difícil ahora.
Why do I keep on letting him fool me?
¿Por qué le sigo creyendo?
Hey, servant.
Oye, sirvienta.
You said money is what you need the most,
Dijiste que el dinero es lo que más necesitas,
but money will give you happiness.
porque te dará felicidad.
Therefore, happiness must be what you really need the most.
Por lo tanto, lo que necesitas es felicidad.
You don't even know anything about me.
No sabe nada de mí.
I have no interest whatsoever in a mere woman's happiness,
No tengo ningún interés en la felicidad de una mujer,
so I will repay you with money.
así que te pagaré con dinero.
We should look for it together.
Deberíamos salir a pedir ayuda.
-Are we going the right way? -I'm not sure.
- ¿Es este el camino? - No estoy segura.
I think we're lost.
Creo que estamos perdidos.
You're calmer than I expected you to be.
Pareces calmada.
I have to stay calm, of course.
Debo mantener la calma.
I'm your guardian at the moment.
Soy su guardiana por el momento.
"Guardian"?
¿Guardiana?
Yes.
Sí.
You may find it hard to believe, but I have a medical license.
Quizá no me crea, pero tengo licencia médica.
I hope your underling or colleague, whoever he is, went the right way.
Espero que su sirviente, o lo que sea, esté bien.
We shouldn't keep going.
No deberíamos seguir.
We should go back.
Regresemos.
-I've been wanting to say that. -Hey, I'll lead the way.
Ya quería decir eso.
Hey, servant.
Oye, sirvienta.
This is your last warning.
Esta es tu última advertencia. Pon atención.
I'm not "Hey." You have to call me Lord Habaek.
No me llames "oye", llámame "señor Habaek".
The God of Water, the next king of the Land of Water,
El dios del Agua, próximo rey del Reino del Agua,
and the next emperor of the divine world,
y emperador del mundo divino,
Habaek.
Habaek.
Now, it's your turn to listen up.
Ahora tú escucha.
My name is Yun So-a, not "Servant."
Me llamo Yun So-a, no "sirvienta".
Since I'm acting as your guardian now,
Como soy tu guardiana por ahora, sería bueno que me llamaras Dra. Yun.
If you don't want to do that, please at least call me Ms. Yun.
O al menos llámame Srta.Yun.
Are we clear?
¿Está claro?
How insolent.
Qué insolente.
-What is it? -Run!
- ¿Qué pasa? - ¡Corre!
Wait, let's get in the car. Gosh!
Entremos al auto. ¡Cielos!
The trunk!
¡El maletero!
Why is it all quiet now?
¿Por qué se calló?
I think it's gone.
Creo que se fue.
-Are you okay? -I'm very uncomfortable right now.
- ¿Estás bien? - Estoy muy incómodo.
Pardon?
¿Qué?
Don't move. You're making it worse.
Para. Lo estás empeorando.
Okay.
Está bien.
I think it's gone. Let's open it and see.
Creo que se fue. Veamos.
What is that?
¿Qué es eso?
Gosh, it smiled! It actually smiled.
¡Me sonrió, en verdad lo hizo!
What a crazy boar!
¡Ese jabalí está loco!
Lord Habaek.
Señor Habaek.
Can you walk?
¿Puedes caminar?
Let's rest up for a few minutes.
Descansemos un poco.
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
I got lost in the woods and met a hunter.
Me perdí y me topé con un cazador.
I'm so glad he came with me.
Menos mal que vino.
Where is he?
¿Dónde está?
He followed the boar.
Siguió al jabalí.
Did you get hurt?
¿Se lastimó?
Well, I thought you couldn't drive.
Creí que no sabías conducir.
I couldn't.
Así es.
Then what's happening now?
¿Y qué haces ahora?
I'm a good driver now.
Estoy conduciendo.
I've never done this before, but it's fun.
Nunca había hecho esto, pero es divertido.
What?
¿Qué?
Does that mean you don't have a driver's license?
Espera, ¿no tienes licencia de conducir?
-What is a driver's license? -Hey!
¿Qué es una licencia de conducir?
Just get some rest!
¡Solo descansa!
This is a huge honor for you, so don't reject my kind gesture.
Esto es un gran honor, así que agradécelo.
I am just doing what I should do as the generous and dutiful god that I am.
Solo cumplo con mi deber,
Hey!
¡Oye!
Don't worry.
No se preocupe.
Lord Habaek possesses some incredible abilities
El señor Habaek posee habilidades que no podría ni imaginar.
Abilities, my foot. Pull over right now!
Patrañas, ¡detente!
I said, pull over!
¡Dije que te detengas!
Is this where you live?
¿Aquí vives?
-Did you lie to us? -What are you talking about? I lied?
¿Nos mentiste?
Anyway,
En fin,
thank you for everything today.
gracias por todo hoy.
It happened a long time ago.
Fue hace mucho tiempo.
An unknown ancestor of yours made a promise with the gods.
Un ancestro tuyo le prometió a los dioses
He made a pledge that his family would serve the gods for generations.
que su familia le serviría a los dioses por generaciones.
You didn't make that promise, but that's beside the point.
No fuiste tú, pero eso no importa.
You're a descendant of the man who made that promise.
Eres la descendiente de ese hombre.
Therefore, you must serve me if I want you to.
Así que debes servirme.
Take me to your house.
Llévame a tu casa.
No. You can go to the hospital instead.
No, pero deberías ir al hospital.
If you refuse, you will suffer.
Si te niegas, sufrirás.
It doesn't matter because I'm already having a hard enough time.
No me importa, ya estoy sufriendo lo suficiente.
You're right.
Y tienes razón.
Happiness may be what I truly want
Puede que realmente quiera la felicidad, porque estoy exhausta.
So, do me a favor...
Hazme un favor
and leave me alone.
y déjame en paz.
Please.
Por favor.
I can't believe she still hasn't realized her fate
No puedo creer que no acepte su destino después de todo lo que le enseñé.
How foolish.
Qué tonta.
I guess I have no choice.
No tengo otra opción.
Namsuri.
Namsuri, intenté no hacer esto por lo que dijiste.
But now, I have no choice.
Pero no tengo opción.
But, my lord,
Pero, mi señor, su poder podría…
I shall grace you with my blessing,
Te daré mi bendición,
so wake up already.
así que despierta.
Don't you feel like something in your heart...
¿No sientes algo en tu corazón…?
Why did I close my eyes?
¿Por qué cerré los ojos?
Doesn't it feel like something in your heart's smacking your head?
¿No sientes que te intenta decir algo?
-Absolutely not! -You slow-witted woman! I'm right here!
- ¡No! - ¡Mujer necia, estoy aquí!
Gosh, what a psycho!
¡Está loco!
-It must be fate. -You now belong to the deity.
- Debe ser el destino. - Ahora me perteneces.
-You're wrong. -I'm so sick of this nonsense about gods.
- Te equivocas. - Estoy harta de los dioses.
Accept your fate, or you must go through everything.
Acepta tu destino o sufrirás.
What do you mean by "everything"?
Esto no puede ser.
No!
¡No!
-She's falling! -Get her!
¡Se caerá!
Please save me.
Sálvame, por favor.
Will we leave right away?
¿Iremos enseguida?
Yes, I left while he was painting me.
Sí, me fui mientras me pintaba.
Exactly.
Le hubiera dicho que volviera después.
Why are you punishing him?
¿Por qué lo castiga?
EPILOGUE
EPÍLOGO
When did I punish him?
¿Lo castigué?
When is Lord Habaek coming back?
¿Cuándo volverá el señor Habaek?
I should've drawn his eyes when I had the chance to.
Debí pintar sus ojos cuando pude.